<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>skupper-router on Fernando Giorgetti - about me</title>
    <link>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/tags/skupper-router/</link>
    <description>Recent content in skupper-router on Fernando Giorgetti - about me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Fernando Giorgetti</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:19:33 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fgiorgetti.github.io/tags/skupper-router/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Skupper service ingress through containers</title>
      <link>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20240322-skupper-podman-ingresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:19:33 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20240322-skupper-podman-ingresses/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In order to evaluate some strategies for dealing with service ingresses, when running the skupper-router with Podman or Docker, I have used the simple scenario below as the foundation for this study:
The router component is connect to the host network, which avoids restarts when extra ports need to be bound.
In this topology we have two workloads.
my-service - nginx server my-tcp-service - iperf3 server They are exposed through the skupper-router container, which is binding ports 8080 (for nginx) and 5201 (for iperf3) on the host machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running skupper-router containers with compose</title>
      <link>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20240320-router-with-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 09:14:27 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20240320-router-with-compose/</guid>
      <description>A compose file can also be an interesting way to run a static bundle for skupper-routers. Here I am using a two routers network, named west and east.
The west router has an inter-router link (secured with TLS) defined to connect with the east one (using skupper-router-east hostname).
All the configuration, sample certificates and compose files can be downloaded by clicking the following link: Example files (tarball).
Once you extract the tarball, you will find a new directory named example which contains the compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with kube files using Podman</title>
      <link>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20240319-podman-kube-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 10:19:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20240319-podman-kube-play/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this exercise is to create two skupper-router containers named skupper-router-east and skupper-router-west with Podman, exposing a TLS AMQP listener on the east router, with all generated credentials and router configuration included as Kubernetes descriptors (using YAML), so that these YAML files can be loaded with podman kube play to spin up the two router pods.
All files mentioned here, can be found below.
Deploying this sample To deploy this sample, run: .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
