<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Fernando Giorgetti - blog</title>
    <link>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/categories/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Fernando Giorgetti - blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Fernando Giorgetti</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:21:47 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fgiorgetti.github.io/categories/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>File Watcher With Fsnotify</title>
      <link>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20220823-file-watcher-with-fsnotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:21:47 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20220823-file-watcher-with-fsnotify/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we need to watch for modifications in specific locations in the filesystem, reacting to them differently.&#xA;As an example, an alert could be triggered if a specific file is modified or a backup procedure could start as new files are created into specific directories.&#xA;There are several tools and libraries to help doing that, but since I am evaluating libraries in Go, I have decided to play with fsnotify and write a bit about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining your Skupper Virtual Application Network with Gitops</title>
      <link>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20210129-skupper-and-gitops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 18:27:23 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fgiorgetti.github.io/posts/20210129-skupper-and-gitops/</guid>
      <description>Hybrid Cloud using Skupper Skupper enables service communication, transparently, across multiple Kubernetes clusters.&#xA;For more information about Skupper, as well as documentation and great examples, please visit https://skupper.io/.&#xA;This article demonstrates how to setup and maintain a Virtual Application Network (VAN) using Skupper.&#xA;The standard documented approach for setting up a Skupper network, is through the use of its Command Line Interface (CLI) tool named skupper.&#xA;Following its documentation and some examples, you will connect your cloud applications through a set of imperative commands that will help you setting everything up.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
